export const AGRICULTURALSCIENCEA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The most important factor that determines the rate of agricultural development in a country is the",
A: "readiness of farmers to adopt agricultural research results.",
B: "quantity of herbicides used in the country.",
C: "number of machinery available in the country.",
D: "provision of raw materials for industries.",
answer: "A. readiness of farmers to adopt agricultural research results.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following industries does not use an agricultural raw material for its production?",
A: "Textile",
B: "Cement",
C: "Confectionery",
D: "Soap",
answer: "B. Cement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Peasant farmers sell their agricultural produce immediately after harvesting because",
A: "stored produce would be lost to pests.",
B: "storage facilities are inadequate.",
C: "stored produce lose their quality.",
D: "the produce are perishable.",
answer: "B. storage facilities are inadequate.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Subsistence agriculture involves the use of",
A: "agro-chemicals.",
B: "crude farm tools.",
C: "farm machinery.",
D: "fertilizers.",
answer: "B. crude farm tools.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Land use is influenced by the following except",
A: "fallowing.",
B: "population growth.",
C: "climatic conditions.",
D: "topography.",
answer: "A. fallowing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Harmattan wind accelerates",
A: "crop growth.",
B: "drying of grains.",
C: "decomposition.",
D: "photosynthesis.",
answer: "B. drying of grains.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The chemical weathering of rocks represented by the equation below 4FeCO3 + O2 → 2Fe2O3 + 4CO2  is",
A: "solution.",
B: "hydrolysis.",
C: "hydration.",
D: "oxidation",
answer: "D. oxidation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following rocks is formed from shale?",
A: "Gneiss",
B: "Limestone",
C: "Slate",
D: "Dolomite",
answer: "C. Slate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The following factors affect rock weathering except",
A: "water.",
B: "carbonation.",
C: "temperature.",
D: "ammonification.",
answer: "D. ammonification.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Wind erosion can be controlled by",
A: "ridging across the slope.",
B: "practising contour farming.",
C: "planting trees across wind direction.",
D: "ridging along the direction of wind.",
answer: "C. planting trees across wind direction.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A soil is said to be acidic if the pH is",
A: "6.0-6.5.",
B: "7.0-7.5.",
C: "8.0-8.5.",
D: "9.0-9.5.",
answer: "A. 6.0-6.5.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. One major element in agricultural lime is",
A: "iron.",
B: "phosphorus.",
C: "calcium.",
D: "sodium.",
answer: "C. calcium.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The most important effect of rain on soil nutrients is that it brings about",
A: "leaching.",
B: "evaporation.",
C: "transpiration.",
D: "drainage.",
answer: "A. leaching.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The nutrients lost from the soil can be replenished by the following practices except",
A: "cover cropping.",
B: "continuous cropping.",
C: "crop rotation.",
D: "liming.",
answer: "B. continuous cropping.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In green manuring, the mucuna plant is used because it",
A: "releases nitrogen to the soil.",
B: "controls leaching of nutrients.",
C: "checks percolation of water.",
D: "reduces run-off speed.",
answer: "A. releases nitrogen to the soil.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A soil sample containing 60% sand, 20% silt and 10% clay particles can be described as",
A: "sandy loam.",
B: "silty loam.",
C: "clayey loam.",
D: "silty clay.",
answer: "A. sandy loam.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The most efficient irrigation practice on large scale farms in West Africa is",
A: "overhead irrigation.",
B: "basin irrigation.",
C: "underground irrigation.",
D: "Shadoof irrigation.",
answer: "A. overhead irrigation.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Solar energy assists in checking pests multiplication by",
A: "suffocation.",
B: "dehydration.",
C: "decomposition.",
D: "hydration.",
answer: "B. dehydration.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following tools is not used in tillage operation?",
A: "Hoe",
B: "Mattock",
C: "Pick-axe",
D: "Mallet",
answer: "D. Mallet",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. An incubator is used for",
A: "candling eggs.",
B: "brooding chicks.",
C: "hatching fertile eggs.",
D: "storing eggs.",
answer: "C. hatching fertile eggs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following statements about produce storage is false?",
A: "Aeration is necessary for stored produce",
B: "High temperature and high moisture content predispose grains to spoilage",
C: "The storage life of seeds varies with the species and the environment",
D: "High moisture content is crucial for prolonged storage",
answer: "D. High moisture content is crucial for prolonged storage",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following sources of farm power is the least utilized in West Africa?",
A: "Human",
B: "Animal",
C: "Electricity",
D: "Biogas",
answer: "D. Biogas",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Large-scale storage of grains is best done in",
A: "barns.",
B: "cold rooms.",
C: "cribs.",
D: "silos.",
answer: "D. silos.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. One of the planting materials used in propagating yam is",
A: "rhizome.",
B: "sett.",
C: "crown.",
D: "Sucker",
answer: "A. rhizome.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A farmer who has no funds to purchase fertilizer and manure to enrich his farmland is advised to practice",
A: "mixed cropping.",
B: "monoculture.",
C: "crop rotation.",
D: "silviculture.",
answer: "C. crop rotation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Elaeis guineensis grows best in an area with annual rainfall of about",
A: "760 mm – 800 mm.",
B: "2,000 mm – 3,000 mm.",
C: "3,500 mm-4,000 mm.",
D: "4,500 mm – 5,000 mm.",
answer: "B. 2,000 mm – 3,000 mm.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A crop with parallel leaf venation that completes its life cycle in three months is",
A: "a perennial dicotyledonous plant.",
B: "a perennial monocotyledonous plant.",
C: "an annual monocotyledonous plant.",
D: "an annual dicotyledonous plant.",
answer: "C. an annual monocotyledonous plant.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following crops is a forage legume?",
A: "Elephant grass",
B: "Mucuna",
C: "Spear grass",
D: "Northern gamba grass",
answer: "B. Mucuna",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Parboiling of rice involves",
A: "soaking for short time and drying.",
B: "boiling for long time and drying.",
C: "boiling for short time and drying.",
D: "soaking for long time and drying.",
answer: "C. boiling for short time and drying.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following cultural practices would be considered suitable for the successful growth of the crop?",
A: "Mulching",
B: "Irrigation",
C: "Ridging",
D: "Manuring",
answer: "B. Irrigation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Assuming moisture supply and nutrients are adequate, the growth of crop X in the area would likely be",
A: "normal.",
B: "slow.",
C: "fast.",
D: "retarded.",
answer: "A. normal.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The main objective of growing ornamental plants is to",
A: "provide income for florists.",
B: "beautify the environment.",
C: "provide medicinal herbs.",
D: "control soil erosion.",
answer: "B. beautify the environment.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Viral diseases of crops can best be managed through",
A: "vector control.",
B: "planting resistant varieties.",
C: "carrying out cultural practices.",
D: "sterilizing farm equipment.",
answer: "B. planting resistant varieties.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Tikka is a fungal disease of",
A: "groundnut.",
B: "plantain.",
C: "cowpea.",
D: "citrus.",
answer: "A. groundnut.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Root knot disease of tomato can be controlled by applying",
A: "insecticides.",
B: "nematicides.",
C: "avicides.",
D: "herbicides.",
answer: "B. nematicides.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Bean beetles cause the following damages except",
A: "reduction in market value.",
B: "spoilage of quality of grains.",
C: "reduction in germination ability.",
D: "discolouration of testa.",
answer: "A. reduction in market value.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A systemic herbicide is best for the control of",
A: "annual weeds.",
B: "perennial weeds.",
C: "monocotyledonous weeds.",
D: "dicotyledonous weeds.",
answer: "B. perennial weeds.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The hereditary units of inheritance that are responsible for the transmission of characters from parents their offspring are the",
A: "chromosomes.",
B: "genes.",
C: "ovules.",
D: "zygotes.",
answer: "B. genes.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. In the alimentary canal of poultry, grit could be found in the",
A: "caecum.",
B: "gizzard.",
C: "intestine.",
D: "proventriculus.",
answer: "B. gizzard.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Lactation in farm animals is positively affected by",
A: "frightening and irritating the animals.",
B: "subjecting the animals to pain or noise.",
C: "regular extraction of milk from their udders.",
D: "starving the animals of food and water.",
answer: "C. regular extraction of milk from their udders.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Good management practices in pastures include the following except",
A: "continuous grazing.",
B: "rotational grazing.",
C: "control of weeds.",
D: "use of fertilizers.",
answer: "A. continuous grazing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following diseases is caused by a bacterium?",
A: "Foot and mouth disease",
B: "Rinderpest",
C: "Brucellosis",
D: "Newcastle disease",
answer: "C. Brucellosis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following statements is false about the oestrus cycle? It is",
A: "the end of one heat period to the beginning of another.",
B: "regulated by a hormone called oestrogen.",
C: "different from one animal species to another.",
D: "controlled by a hormone called progesterone.",
answer: "A. the end of one heat period to the beginning of another.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Needle teeth in piglets are removed to",
A: "prevent wounding of sow’s teats.",
B: "prevent piglets from biting one another.",
C: "make piglets grow faster.",
D: "facilitate suckling by piglets.",
answer: "A. prevent wounding of sow’s teats.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. In the domestic fowl, a cock could be differentiated from a hen by its possession of",
A: "small combs.",
B: "prominent spurs.",
C: "dull feathers.",
D: "thin shanks.",
answer: "B. prominent spurs.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The system of keeping a goat tied to a pole for grazing is known as",
A: "paddocking.",
B: "tethering.",
C: "ranching.",
D: "browsing.",
answer: "B. tethering.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The process of mating in sheep is termed",
A: "treading.",
B: "courting.",
C: "tupping.",
D: "servicing.",
answer: "C. tupping.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. One of the disadvantages of poultry production is that",
A: "return per unit space is high.",
B: "there are early returns on capital.",
C: "eggs have quick turn over.",
D: "capital outlay is high.",
answer: "D. capital outlay is high.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. In animal nutrition, iodine is essential for the production of",
A: "oxygen.",
B: "thyroxine.",
C: "insulin.",
D: "progesterone.",
answer: "B. thyroxine.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. In poultry nutrition, the minerals that prevent the laying of thin-shelled eggs are",
A: "calcium and phosphorus.",
B: "sodium and calcium.",
C: "phosphorus and sodium.",
D: "sulphur and phosphorus.",
answer: "A. calcium and phosphorus.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. Methods of rangeland improvement do not include",
A: "controlled grazing.",
B: "stocking rate.",
C: "burning.",
D: "paddocking.",
answer: "C. burning.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. The pox diseases in livestock are caused by",
A: "bacteria.",
B: "viruses.",
C: "protozoa.",
D: "fungi.",
answer: "B. viruses.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. Fertilizers are applied to fishponds to serve as",
A: "bait for fish.",
B: "food for fish.",
C: "nutrients for plankton.",
D: "water purifier.",
answer: "C. nutrients for plankton.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. Which of the following statements about fish smoking is false?",
A: "Smoking increases the protein content of fish.",
B: "During smoking the heat cooks the fish.",
C: "The smoke gives the fish a special aroma.",
D: "Smoke kills some of the bacteria present.",
answer: "A. Smoking increases the protein content of fish.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. The most effective breeding system for preventing sexually transmitted diseases in farm animals is by",
A: "artificial insemination.",
B: "hand mating.",
C: "crossbreeding.",
D: "inbreeding.",
answer: "A. artificial insemination.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. Determine the weight gained by a lamb within a normal year if its birth weight was 2.800 kg and it gained 53 g per day on the average.",
A: "14.840 kg.",
B: "16.545 kg.",
C: "19.345 kg.",
D: "22.145 kg.",
answer: "C. 19.345 kg.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. Artificial scarcity of agricultural produce is often caused by the following marketing agents except",
A: "wholesalers.",
B: "middlemen.",
C: "farmers.",
D: "co-operatives.",
answer: "D. co-operatives.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. In West Africa, farm labour is on the decline because of",
A: "increase in urban-rural migration.",
B: "increase in rural-urban drift.",
C: "increase in cost of hiring labour.",
D: "decrease in white collar jobs.",
answer: "B. increase in rural-urban drift.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. Which of the following statements is not true of cooperative societies?",
A: "Members cooperate to protect their interest",
B: "They promote thrifting and crediting",
C: "Their operation cost is low",
D: "Membership is restricted to the literate farmers",
answer: "D. Membership is restricted to the literate farmers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. The best method for the effective teaching of agriculture in schools is by",
A: "instructions and on-farm practical.",
B: "instructions and field trips.",
C: "instructions only.",
D: "laboratory instructions.",
answer: "B. instructions and field trips.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]